Hwee Shan Wong

Software Developer



About me

Hi, my name is Hwee and currently a software engineer in Natwest Group. I am passionate about developing tools and products to boost engineering experience for other engineers. I have experience in delivering microservices using the twelve-factor app methodology, designing even-driven architecture and have also worked on implementing infrastructure solutions and services.

Grew up trilingual (English, Mandarin, Malay).

Skills



Contact



hweeshan_wong@hotmail.com

+44 7424 586 826

HweeWong

Experience

Software Engineer

Natwest Group, Edinburgh | since April 2018

- Automated the onboarding process to developer tools. Reduced cycle time from 48 hrs to 5 mins.
- Delivered Spring Boot Java microservices in event-driven architecture and have deep understanding of the system design.
- Collaborated closely with customers/SMEs in agile development.
- >50% reduction in cycle time from development to release
- · Cultivated the culture of BDD, TDD within the team which enhanced system reliability and team's devops metrics.
- Presented proof of concepts for different IAM integration of tools.
- Led migration work for on-prem SaaS product.

Technology Service Analyst

Natwest Group, Edinburgh | Sep 2017 - Apr 2018

- · Migrated server data from bespoke tools to ServiceNow CMDB for better consolidation of data within the enterprise.
- · Embedded agile methodology for the project through creation of short-term, manageable goals and Kanban dashboards.
- Improved communications plans with stakeholders to ensure transparency and effective communication.

Chemical Engineer

Merck, Sharp & Dohme (MSD), Newcastle | Aug 2015 - Sep 2016

- Supported technical operations in solid-dose tablet production facility and operated within GMP standards.
- Led incidents/deviations investigations to identify root causes using Lean Six Sigma methodologies.
- Generated technical memorandums for process improvements. Implementation of new design reduced operation downtime.

Education

MEng Chemical Engineering with Industrial Experience, University of Manchester

Sep 2013 - Jun 2017

First Class Honors

A Levels, Taylor's College Jan 2012 - Jun 2013

4A* in Chemistry, Biology, Physics, Mathematics



Contributions

Women In Tech Secretariat

Actively supporting gender balance within workplace. Running python workshops to promote engineering.

STEM Ambassador STV Big Scot Quiz

Encouraging students to appreciate Science. Technology, **Engineering and Math** (STEM) subjects by engaging students in interesting experiments concurrently in and sharing work experience.

Volunteer

Volunteered to assist and coordinate the running of a major, high-profile charity event that was held Edinburgh and Glasgow which raised £35,000.